### **Reed Morrison**

# reed.morrison@gmail.com

## **LINKS**

Website: <a href="https://tinselcity.github.io">https://tinselcity.github.io</a></a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/tinselcity">https://github.com/tinselcity</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/reed-morrison

Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/tinselcity1

### **STATEMENT**

Software engineer with experience in the development of web servers, and cloud based security applications. Lead teams, and created several successful product lines at a reasonably large scale (in number of customers and traffic). Interested in web servers, web application security, and distributed computing.

### **SKILLS**

### **Software Development:**

Topics: Clients/Servers, Internet Protocols, (HTTP/H2, TLS, UDP, TCP/IP), WAF's

• Languages: C, C++, Python, Bash, Golang

Process: Agile/SAFe

### **Education:**

B.S. Electrical Engineering (University of California Davis)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Principal Software Engineer (CDN) Edgio, Playa Vista, CA

(September 2019 - Present)

Edge front-end server development, including: L7 load balancing, consistent hashing/cache key generation with scaling for popular content, secure highly multi-tenant TLS termination (client to edge). Developed concepts for customer configurations with support for self-service and faster edge distribution.

# Security Core Development Lead (CDN) Edgio, Playa Vista, CA

(August 2016 - September 2019)

Lead security application development for a large global CDN with thousands of customers. Product lines included: WAF, L7 rate-limiting, and basic bot mitigation. Developed multi-tenant ModSecurity conformant WAF allowing for improved performance, and scale. Conducted code reviews, audits, and large-ish refactors of several internal and external team projects.

Senior Software Engineer (CDN) Edgio, Santa Monica, CA

(August 2013 - August 2016)

# WAF and Rate-Limiting back office

Designed and developed the security product back-office supporting the WAF and L7 rate-limiting products, including: configuration API's, fast global config distribution, logging pipelines, and an HA data cluster with customer facing dashboard API's.

# **Edge to Origin TLS configuration**

Developed customer "Edge to Origin" TLS configuration including, hostname validation, cipher specifications, and certificate pinning.

**Software Engineer** CounterTack (Endpoint Security), Santa Monica, CA (April 2011 - July 2013)

## **VM Introspection Solution**

Improved performance and reliability of existing forensics collection/analysis projects. Developed interprocess elastic buffer library with test harness. Removed analysis SW bottlenecks identified via performance profiling. Developed automated testing suite to spin-up/attack VMs, and to verify correctness of forensics results. Optimized VM system collection stack increasing data throughput, and VM performance.

**Embedded Software Engineer** Northrop Grumman Space Technology, Redondo Beach, CA (August 2007 - March 2011)

## **Satellite - Communications System Payload Firmware:**

Lead firmware developer for command and data handling computer. Firmware bootstrapped flight SBC, including run-time initialization, bridge configuration, and ground command-able loading/patching of the flight application. Created requirements, design, and test documentation. Developed suite of SW utilities to facilitate firmware SW unit testing, including an EEPROM file system layout tool, and a diagnostic serial shell supporting program loads/memory dumps/EEPROM burns.

### Satellite -Control System Payload SW Verification:

Led flight SW verification effort including development of test requirements, test-set HW/SW, and verification SW. Verified HW and SW aspects of the target against program requirements. Notable features of the test-set included: JTAG/Serial/1553 I/O, a scriptable remote controlled interface for full-scale remote automation, database uploads, and test vector integration for comparing simulated control laws to actuals running on the target.

**Electrical Engineer** ATK Space and Sensors, Torrance, CA (July 2001 - April 2007)

## **Medical Imaging System:**

For the Wellman Center of Photomedicine, developed a fast data acquisition/storage system for a medical imaging application running on a single board computer. Wrote low overhead high speed file system for managing data stored to a RAID from the SBC via fiber-channel. Co-developed fast B-Spline interpolation and baseband conversion algorithms for an FPGA.

### Laser Radar System:

Developed laser radar data acquisition/processing server application for multi-CPU single board computers. Demanding real-time performance requirements were met by: vectorizing radar algorithms, distributing workload over many CPUs, and optimizing corner turns per cache size. Developed multi-processor notification/communication driver with POSIX-like interfaces.